A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Estate Files, Accession 2008:045 FA1361
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Estate Files, Accession 2008:045
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
FA1361
6.5 Cubic Feet 5 standard record storage boxes
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
LSR Personal Files from Room 5600.
Conditions Governing Access
Restricted from research pending further processing.
- Accession 2008:045, 1
  - Rockefeller, Mary French: General (Box 1)
  - LSR and Rockefeller, Mary French: Marriage License (copy), 1934 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln School (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Materials include some LSR underlining
  - LSR: Correspondence: Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich and John D., Jr. (copies), 1928-1934 (Box 1)
    Copies of LSR letters to AAR and JDR JR.
  - LSR: Princeton University: Senior Thesis, 1932 (Box 1)
    Includes LSR underlining.
  - LSR: Notes: Objectives, Challenges, and Achievements, 1983, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Rockefeller Family: Correspondence, 1952-1986 (Box 1)
    Originals and some copies.
  - Aldrich, Lucy T.: Letters to LSR and MFR, 1952 (Box 1)
    Originals.
  - Maze, Etienne: Letter to LSR, 1983 (Box 1)
    Original.
  - Rockefeller Family: Articles on (Box 1)
  - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell: Draft Copies and Book (Box 2)
  - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell: LSR Signed Buckslips (Box 2)
  - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell: Distribution - General (Box 2)
  - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell: Distribution - Rockefeller Family (Box 2)
  - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell: Letters of Response (Box 2)
  - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell: Distribution - Address Lists (Box 2)
  - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell: Copy of Bessie Dashiell's Death Certificate (Box 2)
  - LSR: Winks Biography: LSR Background (Box 2)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller: Catalyst for Conservation, by Robin W. Winks.
  - LSR: Winks Biography: General (Box 2)
  - LSR: Winks Biography: LSR Personal Distribution (Box 2)
  - LSR: Winks Biography: LSR Inscriptions (Box 2)
  - LSR: Winks Biography: LSR Accompanying Letters (Box 2)
  - LSR: Winks Biography: General Distribution Lists (Box 2)
  - LSR: Winks Biography: Letters of Response (Box 2)
  - Chernow, Ron: Titan - Reviews (Box 2)
  - MSKCC: General (Box 2)
  - MSKCC: Resolution for Dr. Paul M. Marks, 1999 December 14 (Box 2)
  - MSKCC: Kelly, Thomas J., MD (Box 2)
    Chairman of Sloan Kettering Institute
  - MSKCC: Wittes, Robert E., MD (Box 2)
    Physician in Chief
  - MSKCC: Board Meeting (Box 2)
  - MSKCC: Cassileth, Barrie R., Ph.D. (Box 2)
  - Drug Reform: LSR Letter to the New York Times, 1999 May 7 (Box 2)
  - MSKCC?: Dinner announcing Capital Campaign, 2003 January 23 (Box 2)
    Inventory lists under heading of Drug Reform - mistake
  - Property: New York: 834 Fifth Avenue (Box 3)
  - Property: Wyoming: JY Ranch (Box 3)
  - Property: Wyoming: Valley Ranch (Box 3)
  - Property: Woodstock: Echo Acres (Box 3)
  - Property: Woodstock: General (Box 3)
  - Property: U.S. Virgin Islands: Sandy Cay (Box 3)
  - Property: U.S. Virgin Islands: Estate Fountain River (Box 3)
  - Conservation: General (Box 3)
  - Conservation: Hudson River (Box 3)
  - LSR: Pamphlets and Brochures: MSKCC - Rockefeller Outpatient Pavilion (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: MSKCC - Mary and Laurance S. Rockefeller Chapel of Hope and Remembrance (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: MSKCC - Mary and Laurance S. Rockefeller, At the Health Care Chaplaincy (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Kykuit, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Kykuit, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Nine Window by Chagall (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Chagall Window in Memory of Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1981 June 13 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: The Coach Barn (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Pocantico Hills, 1609-1959 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Union Church of Pocantico Hills (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Rockefeller's Gift - First 60 years of the Laboratory of Anthropology, Santa Fe, New Mexico (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Continuing Rockefeller Family Traditions in Philanthropy, 2003 (Box 3)
    1996, revised 2003.
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Brooke Astor: A Birthday for Brooke, by Brendan Gill, 1992 March 5 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Nash Castro, Executive Director of the Palisades Interstate Park Commission, Remarks, 1989 June 15 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures: Unforgettable Dewitt Wallace (Box 3)
    Reader's Digest reprint.
  - LSR: Awards: British Virgin Islands Belonger Ceremony, 2003 September 26 (Box 4)
    LSR letter announcing 2-year transitional program to BVI Officials, 8/1/2003. Letters of response from BVI officials. Letter from the Chief Minister announcing Belonger Status, 9/12/2003. List of Guests, Program, and LSR's Words of Acceptance, 9/26/2003. Belonger Certificate and ID card. press releases, LSR statement for press release. LSR Letters of Appreciation. BVI Belonger Ceremony items sent to Archives, 10/9/2003.
  - LSR: Speeches: 2003 September 26: BVI Belonger Ceremony (Box 4)
    Speeches with back-up material.
  - LSR: Speeches: 2000: Grand Teton National Park Fiftieth Anniversary (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1997 December 13: Governor's Preservation and Parks Award (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1997 September 10: Grand Steward of the Tetons Award (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1992 June 2: Marsh Billings Rockefeller National Historical Park Hearing (Box 4)
    Hearing before the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands, House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs. Speeches with back-up material.
  - LSR: Speeches: 1991 February 16: Woodrow Wilson Award Speech, Princeton University (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1990 May 17: Congressional Gold Medal Award and Acceptance (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1974 December 24: LSR Testimony at Nelson A. Rockefeller Vice Presidential Nomination Hearings (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1971 June 14: Notification of Appointment as Commander of the British Empire (Hon.) (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1996 December 11: Henry L. Diamond Remarks on Fortieth Anniversary of the Virgin Islands National Park (Box 4)
  - LSR: Speeches: 1996 January 20: Award of the Medal of Freedom by President Lyndon Baines Johnson (Box 4)
  - LSR: Financial Reviews (Annual), 1992-1997; 6 files (Box 5)
    Annual Financial Reviews. 1997 includes Reference Book.
  - LSR: Financial Reviews (Annual), 1998-2000, 2002; 4 files (Box 5)
    With LSR marginalia. Two copies of 2002 review, but only one marked up.
  - LSR: Financial Reviews (Annual), 2004 (Box 5)
    With Clayton W. Frye notes.
  - LSR: Plan (1992) (Box 5)
  - LSR: Annual Review, 1993, 1995, 1997-2001, 2003; 8 files (Box 5)
  - LSR: Property: Pocantico Land Sale, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Property: Hawaii: Market Value Appraisal of the Fee Simple Interest in NPS Tract numbers 03-146 - 03-149, Kipahulu, Maui, Hawaii, 1995 October 18 (Box 5)
  - LSR: Miscellaneous Memoranda (Financial) (Box 5)